Guide to the George Eliot and George Henry Lewes Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Section I. Letters by GEORGE ELIOT to:, 1877 Feb 13
  - D'Albert-Durade, Alexandre Louis François, 1804-1886
    - ----, 1864 Jun 24 (Box 2)
      Tinker 897
    - ----, 1865 Jan 12 (Box 2)
      Tinker 898
    - ----, 1866 Sep 21 (Box 2)
      Tinker 899
    - ALS, 1867 Apr 12 (Box 2)
      Tinker 900
    - ----, 1868 Jan 30 (Box 2)
      Tinker 901
    - ALS, 1871 Jan 27 (Box 2)
    - ----, 1871 Apr 24 (Box 2)
      Tinker 902
    - ----, 1872 Jan 29 (Box 2)
      Tinker 903
    - ----, 1872 Oct 31 (Box 2)
      Tinker 904
    - ----, 1873 Mar 21 (Box 2)
      Tinker 905
    - ----, 1873 Aug 9 (Box 2)
      Tinker 906
    - ----, [1874] Feb 23 (Box 2)
      Tinker 907
    - ----, 1875 Mar 20 (Box 2)
      Tinker 908
    - ----, 1875 Oct 13 (Box 2)
      Tinker 909
    - ----, 1876 Sep 2 (Box 2)
      Tinker 910
    - ----, 1877 Nov 27 (Box 2)
      Tinker 911
    - ----, 1878 Aug 1 (Box 2)
      Tinker 912
    - ----, 1879 Mar 9 (Box 2)
      Tinker 912A
    - ----, 1880 Mar 28 (Box 2)
      Tinker 912B
  - Darwin, Charles Robert, 1809-1882, 1873 Mar 31 (Box 2)
  - Deutsch, Emanuel Oscar Menahem, 1829-1873, [1871] Jul 7 (Box 2)
  - Dew-Smith, A.G., 1879 Sep 11 (Box 2)
  - Doulton, Sir Henry, 1820-l897, 1878 Aug 8 (Box 2)
  - Evans, Isaac Pearson, 1816-1890, 1857 May 26 (Box 2)
    Copy in the hand of J. W. Cross
  - Evans, Robert, 1773-1849, [1842 Feb 28] (Box 2)
    (GE's father)
  - Evans, Robert, 1832-1911
    - (GE's nephew), 1864 Feb 2 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1864 Apr 3 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1866 Aug 14 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1866 Sep 10 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1874 Jun 23 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1874 Sep 26 (Box 3)
  - Evans, Jane (Attenborough); (Mrs. Robert Evans); (GE's sister-in-law)
    - Copy in an unidentified hand, 1864 Feb 12 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1879 Feb 20 (Box 3)
  - Evans, Samuel and Elizabeth; Evans, Samuel, 1777-1858; Evans, Elizabeth (Tomlinson), 1776-1849; (GE's aunt and uncle)
    - Mrs. Evans, 1839 Feb 6 (Box 3)
    - Mrs. Evans, 1839 Mar 5 (Box 3)
    - Mr. Evans, 1840 Feb 26 (Box 3)
    - Mr. Evans, 1840 Aug l0 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1840 Dec 5 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1841 Mar 9 (Box 3)
    - Mr. Evans, 1841 Oct 2 (Box 3)
  - Eve, Florence Nightingale (Cross), 1857-1915 (Box 3)
    See: Cross, Florence Nightingale (Mrs. Henry W. Eve)
  - Ewart, Mary A., 1880 Feb 7 (Box 3)
    This letter is pasted on inside front cover of Romola. Note by Mary A. Ewart on p. [3] (Call number: Eliot IX.4.j.)
  - Faithfull, Emily, 1835-1895, 1873 Aug 23 (Box 3)
  - Gilchrist, Anne (Burrows), 1828-1885 (Mrs. Alexander Gilchrist), 1871 Apr 19
    - ----, 1871 Aug 2 (Box 3)
  - Greville, Sabine Matilda (Thellusson), l878 Sep 26 (Box 3)
  - Hanson, Blanche Southwood (Lewes), 1872- (Box 3)
    See: Lewes, Blanche Southwood (Mrs. R. J. E. Hanson)
  - Harrison, Frederic, 1831-1923
    - ----, 1866 Jan 5 (Box 3)
      Tinker 913
    - Incomplete, 1866 Jan 9 (Box 3)
      Tinker 914
    - ----, 1866 Jan 12 (Box 3)
      Tinker 915
    - ----, 1866 Jan 22 (Box 3)
      Tinker 916
    - ----, 1866 Jan 31 (Box 3)
      Tinker 917
    - I feel all sorts..., 1866 Apr 10 (Box 3)
      Tinker 918
    - After I had written the enclosed letter..., 1866 Apr 10 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1866] Apr 18 (Box 3)
      Tinker 919
    - ----, 1866 Apr 27 (Box 3)
      Tinker 920
    - ----, 1866 May 4 (Box 3)
      Tinker 921
    - ----, [1866 May 6] (Box 3)
      Tinker 922
    - Incomplete, [1866] May 8 (Box 3)
      Tinker 923
    - ----, [1866 May 23?] (Box 3)
      Tinker 924
    - ----, [1866 May 26] (Box 3)
      Tinker 925
    - ----, [1866 May 29] (Box 3)
      Tinker 926
    - ----, 1866 Aug 4 (Box 3)
      Tinker 927
    - ----, 1866 Aug 15 (Box 3)
      Tinker 928
    - ----, 1867 Feb 18 (Box 3)
      Tinker 929
    - ----, 1867 Nov 7 (Box 3)
      Tinker 930
    - Before we set off..., 1868 May 25 (Box 3)
      Tinker 931
    - Yes, indeed, I..., [1868 May 25] (Box 3)
      Tinker 932
    - ----, 1869 Jun 6 (Box 3)
      Tinker 933
    - ----, 1870 Jan 15 (Box 3)
      Tinker 934
    - ----, 1871 May 7 (Box 3)
      Tinker 935
    - ----, 1872 Apr 3 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1873 Jun 20 (Box 3)
      Tinker 936
    - ----, 1874 Dec 30 (Box 3)
      Tinker 937
    - ----, 1875 Jan 1 (Box 3)
      Tinker 938
    - ----, 1875 Jan 7 (Box 3)
      Tinker 939
    - ----, 1875 Jan 8 (Box 3)
      Tinker 940
    - ----, 1875 Feb 19 (Box 3)
      Tinker 941
    - ----, 1875 Jun 1 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1875] Jun 2 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1875 Jun 9 (Box 3)
      Tinker 942
    - ----, 1875 Jun 15 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1875 Jun 18 (Box 3)
      Tinker 943
    - ----, 1877 Jun 14 (Box 3)
      Tinker 944
    - ----, 1877 Dec 26 (Box 3)
      Tinker 945
    - to Mr. & Mrs. Harrison, 1879 Apr 8 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1879 Jun 10 (Box 3)
      Tinker 946
    - ----, 1880 Apr 15 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1880 Apr 19] (Box 3)
      Tinker 947
  - Harrison, Ethel (Harrison) (Mrs. Frederic Harrison)
    - ----, 1872 Nov 25 (Box 3)
      Tinker 948
    - ----, 1872 Dec 11 (Box 3)
      Tinker 949
    - to Mr. & Mrs. Harrison, filed under Harrison, Frederic, 1879 Apr 8 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1879 May 25 (Box 3)
      Tinker 950
  - Helps, Alice, 1874 Nov 23
    - ----, 1880 Mar 28 (Box 3)
  - Hennell, Charles Christian, 1809-1850
    - With a note by Hennell to Sara Hennell, [1844 Apr] (Box 3)
    - Also addressed to the Brays, [1848 Jun 8] (Box 3)
    - & Sara Hennell and filed under Bray, Charles & Caroline (Box 3)
  - Hennell, Sara Sophia, 1812-1899
    See also under Mr. & Mrs. Charles Bray for letters addressed jointly to them and to Miss Hennell, Mrs. Bray's sister.
    - ----, 1842 Aug 30 (Box 3)
    - Friday, [1842 Sep 16?] (Box 3)
    - Tuesday, [1842 Sep 20] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1842] Nov 3 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1842] Nov 23 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1843] Jan 29 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1843 Mar 15?] (Box 3)
    - ----, 1843 Sep 16 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1843 Oct 9 (Box 3)
    - Sunday, [1844 Mar 3] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1844 Apr 9?] (Box 3)
    - Friday, [1844 Apr] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1844 Aug] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1844 Sep] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1844] Sep 14 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1844] Oct 31 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1845 Apr 6] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1845 Apr 16] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1845 Apr 29] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1845 May] (Box 3)
    - Tuesday, [1845 May] 27 (Box 3)
    - Friday, [1845 Jun 13] (Box 3)
    - Friday evening, [1845 Aug?] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1845 Sep?] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1845 Sep 25] (Box 3)
    - Sunday, [1845 Dec?] (Box 3)
    - You are quite right..., [1845] (Box 3)
    - As I have been obliged..., [1845] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1845 Dec 18] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1845 Dec 31] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1846 Jan 26] (Box 3)
    - I did not receive..., [1846 Jan?] (Box 3)
    - I sent a parcel of M.S...., [1846 Jan?] (Box 3)
    - Thanks, dear Sara..., [1846 Jan?] (Box 3)
    - Will it not please thee..., [1846 Mar 4] (Box 3)
    - Pollianus Achati suo salutem..., [1846 Mar 10?] (Box 3)
    - As Mr. Bray tells me..., [1846 Mar?] (Box 3)
    - I think on the whole..., [1846 Mar?] (Box 3)
    - My soul kisses thee..., [1846 Mar?] (Box 3)
    - Have I really..., [1846 Apr?] (Box 3)
    - I have considered..., [1846 Apr?] (Box 3)
    - I have been guilty..., [1846 Apr 12?] (Box 3)
    - A young lady..., [1846 Apr?] (Box 3)
    - I have no doubt ..., [1846 Apr?] (Box 3)
    - I have been idle..., [1846 Apr?] (Box 3)
    - Health & greetings..., [1846 Apr?] (Box 3)
    - Thou mayst make..., [1846 May?] (Box 3)
    - I will leave the title-page..., [1846 May?] (Box 3)
    - As I believe..., [1846 May?] (Box 3)
    - See what it is to have.., [1846 May 20?] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1846 May 23] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1846 Sep 14?] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1846 Oct 5] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1846 Oct 29] (Box 3)
    - Thursday, [1846 Nov 5] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1848 Nov 15] (Box 3)
    - Thursday, [1846 Nov 26?] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1846 Dec 20] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1847 Feb 18] (Box 3)
    - Sunday, [1847 Feb 28] (Box 3)
    - Sunday, [1847 Apr 4] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1847 Apr 30] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1847 Jun 14] (Box 3)
    - ----, 1847 Sep 16 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1847] Oct 13 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1847 Nov 15] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1847] Nov 27 (Box 3)
    - First page of this letter is missing, [1848 Jan?] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1848] Feb 1 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1848 Feb 21?] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1848 May 25?] (Box 3)
    - Wednesday, [1848 Apr 19] (Box 3)
    - Sunday, [1848 Jun 4] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1848 Jun 23] (Box 3)
    - Friday, [1848 Jul 14] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1848 Nov 23] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1848 Dec] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1849 Jan] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1849 Feb 4] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1849 Feb 9] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1849 Apr 18] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1849 Apr 25] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1849 May] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1849 Jun 5] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1849 Oct 26] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1850 Mar 26] (Box 3)
    - Thursday, [1850 Apr 11] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1850] Dec 24 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1851 Aug 5 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1851] Oct 9 (Box 3)
    - Monday, [1851 Oct 13] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1851 Nov 2] (Box 3)
    - Monday, [1851 Nov 24] (Box 3)
    - Wednesday, [1852 Jan 21] (Box 3)
    - Saturday, [1852 Jan 31] (Box 3)
    - Wednesday, [1852 Apr 21] (Box 3)
    - Monday, [1852 May 17] (Box 3)
    - Wednesday, 1852 Jun 9 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1852 Jun 25] (Box 3)
    - Tuesday, [1852 Jun 29] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1852] Jul 16 (Box 3)
    - Monday, [1852 Aug 30] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1852] Sep 2 (Box 3)
    - Saturday, [1852 Sep 25] (Box 3)
    - I know your hair will stand, [1852 Sep] (Box 3)
    - on end... ----, [1852] Oct 12 (Box 3)
    - Monday, [1852 Oct 18] (Box 3)
    - Tuesday, [1852 Nov 23] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1853 Jan 3] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1853 Jan 10] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1853 Mar 19] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1853 Mar 28] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1853 Apr 4] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1853 Jun 25] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1853 Jun 28] (Box 3)
    - Wednesday, [1853 Jul 27] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1853 Aug 18] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1853 Oct 1] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1853 Oct 22] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1853 Nov 15] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1853 Nov 18] (Box 3)
    - Friday morning, [1853 Nov 25] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1854] Jan 18 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1854 Jan 17] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1854] Feb 6 (Box 3)
    - Saturday, [1854 Feb 11] (Box 3)
    - Monday, [1854 Feb 27] (Box 3)
    - Tuesday, [1854 Feb 28] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1854 Mar 9] (Box 3)
    - Friday, [1854 Mar 31] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1854 Apr 3] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1854 Apr 21] (Box 3)
    - Wednesday, [1854 Apr 26] (Box 3)
    - Saturday, [1854 Apr 29] (Box 3)
    - Sunday, [1854 May 7] (Box 3)
    - Wednesday, [1854 May 17] (Box 3)
    - Saturday, [1854 Jun 3] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1854] Jun 12 (Box 3)
    - Monday, [1854 Jul 10] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1854] Oct 31 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1854 Nov 22] (Box 3)
    - ----, 1855 Jan 9 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1855 Mar 16 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1855 Jun 17 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1855 Jun 23 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1855] Jul 21 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1855 Jul 28] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1855] Aug 24 (Box 3)
    - Thursday, [1855 Sep 13] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1855] Oct 16 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1855] Nov 29 (Box 3)
    - Saturday, [1855 Dec 15?] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1856 Jan 18] (Box 3)
    - Monday, [1856 Jan 28] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1856] Feb 19 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1856] Feb 25 (Box 3)
    - Tuesday, [1856 Feb 26] (Box 3)
    - Sunday, [1856 Apr 6] (Box 3)
    - Thursday, [1856 Apr 10] (Box 3)
    - ----, 1856 Jun 29 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1856 Jul 29 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1856 Sep 5] (Box 3)
    - ----, 1856 Sep 22 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1856] Dec 9 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1856] Dec 17 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1857 Jan 26 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1857 Feb 24] (Box 3)
    - ----, 1857 Mar 2 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1857 Mar 5] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1857 Mar 12] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1857] Mar 24 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1857] Mar 27 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1857] Apr 16 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1857] May 22 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1857 Jun 5] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1857 Jun 16] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1857] Aug 19 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1557 Sep 21 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1857 Oct 20 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1857 Nov 9] (Box 3)
    - Monday, [1857 Nov 23] (Box 3)
    - ----, 1857 Dec 13 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1858 Jan 17 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1858 Mar 2 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1858] Mar 27 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1858 Apr 17 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1858 May 10/13 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1858 Jun 14 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1858 Jul 28 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1858] Sep 4 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1858 Sep 5] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1858 Oct 2] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1858] Oct 6 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1858] Oct 11 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1858 Nov 6 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1859 Feb 19 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1859] Feb 26 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1859 Mar 21] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1859 Apr 11] (Box 3)
    - ----, 1859 Apr 15 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1859 Apr 19] (Box 3)
    - ----, 1859 May 19 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1859] May 21 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1859 Jun 16 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1859 Jun 24] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1859 Jun 22] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1859] Aug 15 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1859] Aug 23 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1859] Aug 29 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1859 Sep 4 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1859] Oct 10 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1859 Nov 11 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1859] Nov 14 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1859 Dec 5] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1858 Dec 30] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1860 Jan 9] (Box 3)
    - ----, 1860 Jul 2 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1860 Jul 7 (Box 3)
    - Postscript at end of GHL's letter to Sara Hennell. Filed with GHL letters, 1860 Jul 9 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1860 Aug 6 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1860 Aug 27 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1860 Oct 26] (Box 3)
    - ----, [1860] Nov 13 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1860 Dec 20 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1861 Jan 16] (Box 3)
    - ----, 1861 Feb 8 (Box 3)
    - ----, [1861 Feb 20] (Box 3)
    - ----, 1861 Apr 13 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1861 Jun 19 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1861 Jul 2 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1861 Jul 12 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1861 Jul 30 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1861 Aug 12 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1861 Sep 18 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1861 Oct 6 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1861 Nov 22 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1861 Dec 6 (Box 3)
    - ----, 1862 Jan 14 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1862] Feb 3 (Box 4)
    - Saturday, [1862 Feb 8] (Box 4)
    - Wednesday, [1862 Mar 12] (Box 4)
    - ----, [1862] Mar 27 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1862 Aug 1 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1862 Sep 12 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1862 Oct 3 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1862 Nov 26 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1862 Dec 26 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1863] Jan 1 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1862 [i.e. 1863] (Box 4)
    - ----, Feb 2 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1863 Mar 9 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1863 Jun 10 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1863] Jun 21 (Box 4)
    - Saturday, [1863 Jul 11] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1863 Oct 16 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1863 Dec 26 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1864 Jan 22 (Box 4)
    - Monday, [1864 Mar 7] (Box 4)
    - ----, [1864] Mar 20 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1864] Apr 9 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1864 Apr 30 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1864] Jun 23 (Box 4)
    - Saturday, [1864 Jun 25] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1864 Aug 28 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1864 Aug 30 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1864 Sep 15 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1864 Sep 26 (Box 4)
    - Sunday, [1864 Oct 2] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1864 Nov 23 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1865] Feb 6 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1865 Mar 2 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1865 Mar 8 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1865 May 18 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1865 Sep 14 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1865 Sep 16 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1865] Sep 18 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1865 Sep] (Box 4)
    - ----, [1865] Oct 7 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1865 Oct 16] (Box 4)
    - ----, [1865] Oct 28 (Box 4)
    - Sunday, [1865 Nov 19] (Box 4)
    - ----, [1865] Dec 7 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1865] Dec 21 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1866 Feb 12] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1866 Apr 9 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1866 Aug 10 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1866 Sep 29 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1866 Nov 22 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1866 Dec 7 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1867 Apr 28] (Box 4)
    - ----, [1867] May 13 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1867 Oct 12] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1867 Nov 22 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1867 Dec 26 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1868 Mar 22 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1868 Nov 20 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1869 Feb 4 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1869 Feb 15] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1869 Sep 21 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1869 Nov 15 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1870 May 15] (Box 4)
    - ----, [1870] May 18 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1870 Jun 13 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1870 Aug 12 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1870 Nov 18 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1871 Jan 2 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1871 Nov 19 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1871 Nov 22 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1871 Dec 15 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1872 Jan 4 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1872 Jan 29 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1872 Mar 22 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1872 Aug 1 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1872 Nov 19 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1872] Nov 22 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1872 Dec 20 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1874 Feb 10 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1874 Mar 27 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1874 Apr 23 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1874 Nov 20 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1875 Nov 20 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1876 Nov 22 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1877 May 15 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1877 Nov 16 (Box 4)
    - Sunday, [1877] Nov 23 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1878 Nov 24] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1879 Nov 22 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1880 Dec 4 (Box 4)
  - Hodgson, Mrs. Stewart, [18]78 Aug 25 (Box 4)
    Signed G.H. Lewes
  - Holbeche, Vincent, 1857 Jun 13 (Box 4)
  - Holland, Sir Henry Thurstan, 1826-1914, 1880 Jul 28 (Box 4)
    Copy in an unidentified hand
  - Houghton, Frances [Fanny] Lucy (Evans), 1805-1882
    - (Mrs. Henry Houghton) What could give you the idea..., [1845] (Box 4)
    - Alas, alas!, [1846 Feb?] (Box 4)
    - How are you..., [1847 Jan] (Box 4)
    - You have not, I dare say..., [1848 Feb 27] (Box 4)
    - Mr. Bury has put..., [1848 Apr 17?] (Box 4)
    - I have been expecting, [1848 Apr 20] (Box 4)
    - ----, [1848] May 1 (Box 4)
    - Monday I find it is in vain..., [1848 May?] (Box 4)
    - Saturday Father is not, [1848 May?] (Box 4)
    - apparently... Saturday evening Father is going, [1848 May] (Box 4)
    - on well... Father has made..., [1848 May 25] (Box 4)
    - Fragment: Father has decided..., [1848 May 25] (Box 4)
    - ----, [1848 May 28] (Box 4)
    - ----, [1848 Jun 17] (Box 4)
    - Thursday I hardly know..., [1848 Jun] (Box 4)
    - Father has not been..., [1848 Jun?] (Box 4)
    - Sunday evening There is no material alteration..., [1848 Jul?] (Box 4)
    - Monday evening Father has had, [1848 Jul?] (Box 4)
    - a more... Father has had another..., [1848 Sep?] (Box 4)
    - Mr. Holbeche has been..., [1848 Sep?] (Box 4)
    - Typescript only I have been, [1849 Feb 4?] (Box 4)
    - holding... Thursday evening Father is, [1849 Mar?] (Box 4)
    - very much altered... Wednesday evening I know you are anxious to hear..., [1849 Apr?] (Box 4)
    - Father becomes more..., [1849 Apr?] (Box 4)
    - I think father seems..., [1849 May?] (Box 4)
    - ----, [1849 Jul 23] (Box 4)
    - Typescript only, [1849] Sep 6 (Box 4)
    - Typescript only, [1849] Oct 4 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1850 Feb 4] (Box 4)
    - Typescript only, [1850 Feb 9] (Box 4)
    - Saturday, [1850 Mar 30] (Box 4)
    - Wednesday How have the weeks passed..., [1851 Jul] (Box 4)
    - Thursday, [1851 Sep 18] (Box 4)
    - Sunday, [1851 Sep 21] (Box 4)
    - Typescript only, [1852] Aug 22 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1852] Oct 2 (Box 4)
    - Monday morning, [1852 Dec 27] (Box 4)
    - Typescript only, 1853 Nov 7 (Box 4)
    - Fragment: ...friends-men and women..., [1853 Dec] (Box 4)
    - Typescript only, 1854 Apr 6 (Box 4)
    - Fragment: Chrissy & I..., [1855] Dec 28 (Box 4)
    - Typescript only, 1857 May 3 (Box 4)
    - Fragment: I am going..., 1857 May 26 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1857 Jun 2 (Box 4)
  - Houghton, Richard Monckton Milnes, 1st baron, 1809-1885, 1873 May 13 (Box 4)
    Accompanied by the signed draft of a statement recommending Edward Pigott for the secretaryship of the Royal Academy, 19 May 1873.
  - Joachim, Ellen (Mrs. Henry Joachim), [1876] May 13 (Box 4)
  - Jowett, Benjamin, 1817-1893, 1873 May 12 (Box 4)
  - Knox, Isa (Craig), 1831-1903 (Mrs. John Knox), 1865 Nov 1 (Box 4)
  - Laurence, Samuel, 1861 Apr 8 (Box 4)
  - Lewes, Blanche Southwood, 1872- (Mrs. R. J. E. Hanson) (GHL's granddaughter), 1879 Jul 24 (Box 4)
  - Lewes, Charles and Gertrude; Lewes, Charles Lee, 1842-1891; Lewes, Gertrude (Hill), 1837-1923; (GHL's son and daughter-in-law)
    The letters marked with an asterisk (_) were written by GE and GHL. Unless otherwise noted, the letters are addressed to Charles Lee Lewes.
    - ----, [1861] Apr 25 (Box 4)
    - Filed with letters by GHL, _1861 May 5 (Box 4)
    - ----, _1861 May 17 (Box 4)
    - ----, _1861 May 27 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1862 Mar 10] (Box 4)
    - GHL: [May 10], _1862 May 9 (Box 4)
    - ----, _1867 Aug 23 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1868 Feb 9] (Box 4)
    - to Mr. & Mrs. Charles Lee Lewes, _1868 Jun 27 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1868 Oct 13] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1869 Dec 14 (Box 4)
    - to Mrs. Charles Lee Lewes, 1870 Jul 10 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1870 Jul 21 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1871 Feb 16 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1871 Jun 20 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1871] Jul 10 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1875 Nov 11 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1879 Apr 28] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1879 May 30 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1879 Jun 5 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1879 Jun 10 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1879 Jul 2] (Box 4)
    - ----, [1879 Jul 7] (Box 4)
    - ----, [1879 Jul 10] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1879 Jul 23 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1879 Jul 25 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1879 Jul 31 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1879 Aug 12 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1879 Sep 21 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1879 Oct 3 (Box 4)
    - Saturday, [1879 Oct 18] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1879 Oct 23 (Box 4)
    - Tuesday, [1879 Oct 27] (Box 4)
    - Thursday, [1879 Nov 6?] (Box 4)
    - Tuesday, [1879 Nov 11] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1880 May 12 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1880 May 21 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1880 May 28 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1880 Jun 9 (Box 4)
    - to Mr. & Mrs. Charles Lee Lewes, 1880 [Jul] 7 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1880 Jul 13 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1880 Jul 21 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1880 Aug 28 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1880 Sep 8 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1880 Sep 19 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1880 Oct 7 (Box 4)
  - Lewis, Maria, 1800?-1887
    - ----, 1838 May 26 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1838 Aug 18] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1838 Nov 6 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1839 Feb 27 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1839 Mar 16] (Box 4)
    - ----, [1839] May 20 (Box 4)
    - Wednesday, [1839 Jul 17] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1839 Sep 4 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1839 Oct 30 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1839 Nov 22 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1840 [Feb 13] (Box 4)
    - ----, [1840 Mar 13] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1840 Mar 23 (Box 4)
    - Monday, [1840 Mar 30] (Box 4)
    - Thursday, 1840 May 26 (Box 4)
    - ----, [i.e. May 28] (Box 4)
    - Whitwednesday, [1840 Jun 10] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1840 Jun 23 (Box 4)
    - Monday, [1840 Jul 6] (Box 4)
    - Monday, [1840 Jul 20] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1840 Aug 12 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1840 Sep 17 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1840 Oct 1 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1840 Oct 27 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1840 Dec 5 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1840 Dec 21 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1840 [i.e. 1841] (Box 4)
    - ----, Jan 27 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1841 Feb 11 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1841 Feb 17 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1840 [i.e. 1841] (Box 4)
    - ----, Mar 8 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1841 Mar 11 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1841 Apr 28 (Box 4)
    - Thursday, [1841 May 20] (Box 4)
    - Friday, [1841 Jun 4] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1841 Jun 18 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1841 Jun 21] (Box 4)
    - ----, [1841 Jul 21] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1841 Jul 31- (Box 4)
    - ----, Aug 2 (Box 4)
    - Thursday, [1841 Aug 12] (Box 4)
    - ----, [1841] Aug 20 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1841 Aug 21] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1841 Sep 3-[4] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1841 Oct 1 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1841 Oct 4 (Box 4)
    - ----, 1841 Oct 16 (Box 4)
    - Saturday, [1841 Oct 23] (Box 4)
    - Tuesday, [1841 Nov 2] (Box 4)
    - Saturday, [1841 Nov 13] (Box 4)
    - ----, [1841] Dec 8 (Box 4)
    - Saturday, [1842 Jan 1] (Box 4)
    - ----, 1842 Feb 18 (Box 4)
    - ----, [1842 May 27] (Box 4)